ARNOLD REDOBLADO

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

M 647.407.5270
H 905.479.0725
arnold.redoblado@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/arnoldredoblado
arnoldredoblado.com

PROFILE

An experienced IT professional with over 15 years of experience in the field including comprehensive and applied knowledge of software development, networking concepts/infrastructure, hardware, and 3rd party applications. Highly proficient developer in HTML/CSS, SQL, Ruby on Rails, Javascript/JQuery and Swift. Strong and effective communicator (both written and verbal) and ability to translate technical concepts to non-technical colleagues and clients.

EXPERIENCE

IMS Health (Previously Cegedim): 1998 - 2016

A global information and technology services company providing clients in the healthcare industry with endto-end solutions to measure and improve their performance.

Infrastructure Support Specialist: 2011 - 2016

Responsible for management of database and technical projects as the lead IT advisor in a client-facing role. Clients included senior management sales and marketing professionals in the pharmaceutical industry.

- Successfully designed and created application and database solutions to meet and exceed client expectations for targeted sales and marketing related campaigns
- Develop application to support quality assurance and success metrics reporting
- Streamlined and refactored internal technical processes to improve efficiency and reduce processing time

Programmer Analyst: 2008 - 2011

Responsible for maintaining and supporting a proprietary mobile customer relationship management solution for two major pharmaceutical companies, Abbot and Basilea.

- Effectively developed, tested and implemented new software development solutions to support increased business targets
- Oversaw territory alignments and deployment of new modules and features (ex. inventory tracking and email notifications) to enhance efficiency and effectiveness of products

IT Software, Network and Technical Support (various roles): 1998 – 2008

Various IT software, network and technical support roles with progressive levels of responsibility and oversight. Major roles as primary liaison between senior management and IT department.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

Bitmaker (2016) Web Development

9-week immersive course in web development (SQL, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Ruby on Rails)

Seneca College (2008-2012)

Computer Programming diploma (with Honours) (C++, C#, Java, Perl, Cobol)

RECENT DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Band Aide

Created platform to help local musicians meet other musicians and form new bands. The solution was built with Ruby on Rails along with Devise for login and sessions, Carrierwave and Minimagick for image uploads, Foundation for layout, Geocoder for location services and Google Maps for maps and JQuery/AJAX. Team lead responsible for both front-end and back-end development.

CrowdFundr

Crowdfundr is a web application that profiles and manages social fundraising opportunities for creative projects. The application was built with Ruby on Rails along with Sorcery for logins, Bcrypt for password encryption, Carrierwave and Minimagick for image uploads and Bourbon/Neat for layouts.